{
  "uniqueId": "JLPT N4",
  "name": "JLPT N4 Reading Quiz",
  "article": "a",
  "instructions": "Type the reading of the below word in Hiragana!",
  "questionCreationStrategy": "IMAGE",
  "dictionaryLinkStrategy": "JISHO_QUESTION_WORD",
  "answerTimeLimitStrategy": "JAPANESE_SETTINGS",
  "cardPreprocessingStrategy": "NONE",
  "discordFinalAnswerListElementStrategy": "QUESTION_AND_ANSWER_LINK_QUESTION",
  "scoreAnswerStrategy": "ONE_ANSWER_ONE_POINT",
  "additionalAnswerWaitStrategy": "JAPANESE_SETTINGS",
  "discordIntermediateAnswerListElementStrategy": "CORRECT_ANSWERS",
  "answerCompareStrategy": "CONVERT_KANA",
  "compileImages": true,
  "commentFieldName": "Meaning",
  "cards": [
    {"question":"野菜","answer":["やさい"],"meaning":"vegetable"},
    {"meaning":"a space","question":"間","answer":["あいだ","ま"]},
    {"meaning":"to rise","question":"上る","answer":["あがる","のぼる"]},
    {"question":"郵便局","answer":["ゆうびんきょく"],"meaning":"post office"},
    {"meaning":"flavour","question":"味","answer":["あじ"]},
    {"meaning":"tomorrow","question":"明日","answer":["あす","あした"]},
    {"meaning":"to gather","question":"集る","answer":["あつまる"]},
    {"meaning":"to collect something","question":"集める","answer":["あつめる"]},
    {"meaning":"relief","question":"安心","answer":["あんしん"]},
    {"meaning":"less than","question":"以下","answer":["いか"]},
    {"meaning":"with the exception of","question":"以外","answer":["いがい"]},
    {"meaning":"medical science","question":"医学","answer":["いがく"]},
    {"question":"豚肉","answer":["ぶたにく"],"meaning":"pork"},
    {"meaning":"opinion","question":"意見","answer":["いけん"]},
    {"meaning":"more than, this is all","question":"以上","answer":["いじょう"]},
    {"meaning":"to hurry","question":"急ぐ","answer":["いそぐ"]},
    {"meaning":"once","question":"一度","answer":["いちど"]},
    {"meaning":"to move","question":"動く","answer":["うごく"]},
    {"meaning":"to copy or photograph","question":"写す","answer":["うつす"]},
    {"meaning":"place where things are sold","question":"売り場","answer":["うりば"]},
    {"meaning":"to drive","question":"運転","answer":["うんてん"]},
    {"meaning":"driver","question":"運転手","answer":["うんてんしゅ"]},
    {"meaning":"to exercise","question":"運動","answer":["うんどう"]},
    {"meaning":"rooftop","question":"屋上","answer":["おくじょう"]},
    {"meaning":"to send","question":"送る","answer":["おくる"]},
    {"meaning":"to wake","question":"起す","answer":["おこす"]},
    {"meaning":"to do","question":"行う","answer":["おこなう"]},
    {"meaning":"sound, note","question":"音","answer":["おと","おん","ね"]},
    {"meaning":"to remember","question":"思い出す","answer":["おもいだす"]},
    {"meaning":"to think, to feel","question":"思う","answer":["おもう"]},
    {"meaning":"parents","question":"親","answer":["おや"]},
    {"meaning":"to get off","question":"下りる","answer":["おりる"]},
    {"meaning":"the end","question":"終わり","answer":["おわり"]},
    {"meaning":"assembly hall or meeting place","question":"会場","answer":["かいじょう"]},
    {"meaning":"conversation","question":"会話","answer":["かいわ"]},
    {"meaning":"return","question":"帰り","answer":["かえり"]},
    {"meaning":"fire","question":"火事","answer":["かじ"]},
    {"meaning":"rich man","question":"お金持ち","answer":["おかねもち"]},
    {"meaning":"to commute","question":"通う","answer":["かよう"]},
    {"meaning":"substitute, alternate","question":"代わり","answer":["かわり"]},
    {"meaning":"to consider","question":"考える","answer":["かんがえる"]},
    {"meaning":"spirit, mood","question":"気","answer":["き","け"]},
    {"meaning":"to be heard","question":"聞こえる","answer":["きこえる"]},
    {"meaning":"feeling, mood","question":"気持ち","answer":["きもち"]},
    {"meaning":"kimono","question":"着物","answer":["きもの"]},
    {"meaning":"urgent, steep","question":"急","answer":["きゅう"]},
    {"meaning":"speedy, express","question":"急行","answer":["きゅうこう"]},
    {"meaning":"church","question":"教会","answer":["きょうかい"]},
    {"meaning":"air, atmosphere","question":"空気","answer":["くうき"]},
    {"question":"緑","answer":["みどり"],"meaning":"green, greenery (esp. fresh verdure)"},
    {"meaning":"research","question":"研究","answer":["けんきゅう"]},
    {"meaning":"study room, laboratory","question":"研究室","answer":["けんきゅうしつ"]},
    {"meaning":"sightseeing","question":"見物","answer":["けんぶつ"]},
    {"question":"短い","answer":["みじかい"],"meaning":"short"},
    {"meaning":"the manufacturing industry","question":"工業","answer":["こうぎょう"]},
    {"meaning":"high school","question":"高校","answer":["こうこう"]},
    {"meaning":"high school student","question":"高校生","answer":["こうこうせい"]},
    {"question":"戸","answer":["と"],"meaning":"door (esp. Japanese-style), shutter; window shutter, entrance (to a home), narrows, counter for houses, households, apartments, etc."},
    {"meaning":"headmaster","question":"校長","answer":["こうちょう"]},
    {"meaning":"core, heart","question":"心","answer":["こころ"]},
    {"meaning":"small bird","question":"小鳥","answer":["ことり"]},
    {"meaning":"now, next time","question":"今度","answer":["こんど"]},
    {"meaning":"tonight","question":"今夜","answer":["こんや"]},
    {"meaning":"to get down, to descend","question":"下る","answer":["さがる","くだる"]},
    {"meaning":"to hang, to lower, to move back","question":"下げる","answer":["さげる"]},
    {"meaning":"the month after next","question":"さ来月","answer":["さらいげつ"]},
    {"meaning":"the week after next","question":"さ来週","answer":["さらいしゅう"]},
    {"meaning":"character","question":"字","answer":["じ","あざ"]},
    {"meaning":"method","question":"仕方","answer":["しかた"]},
    {"meaning":"examination","question":"試験","answer":["しけん"]},
    {"meaning":"era","question":"時代","answer":["じだい"]},
    {"meaning":"underwear","question":"下着","answer":["したぎ"]},
    {"meaning":"goods","question":"品物","answer":["しなもの"]},
    {"meaning":"society, public","question":"社会","answer":["しゃかい"]},
    {"meaning":"company president","question":"社長","answer":["しゃちょう"]},
    {"meaning":"to depart","question":"出発","answer":["しゅっぱつ"]},
    {"meaning":"elementary school","question":"小学校","answer":["しょうがっこう"]},
    {"meaning":"to have a meal","question":"食事","answer":["しょくじ"]},
    {"meaning":"groceries","question":"食料品","answer":["しょくりょうひん"]},
    {"meaning":"to notify","question":"知らせる","answer":["しらせる"]},
    {"meaning":"population","question":"人口","answer":["じんこう"]},
    {"meaning":"kindness","question":"親切","answer":["しんせつ"]},
    {"meaning":"newspaper company","question":"新聞社","answer":["しんぶんしゃ"]},
    {"meaning":"water supply","question":"水道","answer":["すいどう"]},
    {"meaning":"western countries","question":"西洋","answer":["せいよう"]},
    {"meaning":"the world","question":"世界","answer":["せかい"]},
    {"question":"庭","answer":["にわ"],"meaning":"garden; yard; courtyard, field (of action); area"},
    {"meaning":"university student","question":"大学生","answer":["だいがくせい"]},
    {"meaning":"important, valuable, serious matter","question":"大事","answer":["だいじ","おおごと"]},
    {"meaning":"typhoon","question":"台風","answer":["たいふう"]},
    {"meaning":"to add a number","question":"足す","answer":["たす"]},
    {"meaning":"correct","question":"正しい","answer":["ただしい"]},
    {"meaning":"to stand something up","question":"立てる","answer":["たてる"]},
    {"meaning":"to build","question":"建てる","answer":["たてる"]},
    {"meaning":"joy","question":"楽しみ","answer":["たのしみ"]},
    {"meaning":"to enjoy oneself","question":"楽む","answer":["たのしむ"]},
    {"meaning":"to be enough","question":"足りる","answer":["たりる"]},
    {"meaning":"strength, power","question":"力","answer":["ちから"]},
    {"meaning":"caution","question":"注意","answer":["ちゅうい"]},
    {"meaning":"junior high school, middle school","question":"中学校","answer":["ちゅうがっこう"]},
    {"meaning":"geography","question":"地理","answer":["ちり"]},
    {"meaning":"shop assistant","question":"店員","answer":["てんいん"]},
    {"meaning":"to go through","question":"通る","answer":["とおる"]},
    {"meaning":"particularly, especially","question":"特に","answer":["とくに"]},
    {"meaning":"special","question":"特別","answer":["とくべつ"]},
    {"meaning":"limited express train (faster than an express train)","question":"特急","answer":["とっきゅう"]},
    {"meaning":"to stop something","question":"止める","answer":["とめる","やめる","とどめる"]},
    {"meaning":"considerably","question":"中々","answer":["なかなか"]},
    {"question":"座る","answer":["すわる"],"meaning":"to sit; to squat, to assume (a position), to hold steady; to hold still"},
    {"meaning":"to enter school or university","question":"入学","answer":["にゅうがく"]},
    {"meaning":"to transport","question":"運ぶ","answer":["はこぶ"]},
    {"meaning":"to begin","question":"始める","answer":["はじめる"]},
    {"meaning":"pronunciation","question":"発音","answer":["はつおん"]},
    {"meaning":"cherry-blossom viewing","question":"花見","answer":["はなみ"]},
    {"meaning":"day, sun","question":"日","answer":["ひ","にち"]},
    {"meaning":"fire","question":"火","answer":["ひ"]},
    {"meaning":"to open an event","question":"開く","answer":["ひらく","あく"]},
    {"meaning":"daytime, during the day","question":"昼間","answer":["ひるま"]},
    {"meaning":"noon break","question":"昼休み","answer":["ひるやすみ"]},
    {"meaning":"literature","question":"文学","answer":["ぶんがく"]},
    {"meaning":"different","question":"別","answer":["べつ"]},
    {"question":"差す","answer":["さす"],"meaning":"to shine, to be visible, to be tinged with, to rise (of water levels); to flow in, to be felt (i.e. as an emotion); to come over one, to hold up (an umbrella, etc.); to put up; to raise, to extend one's arm straight ahead (in dance), to insert; to put in, to wear (a sword) in one's belt; to wear at one's side; to carry under one's arm, to insert one's arm under an opponent's arm, to pole (a boat), to pour; to add (liquid); to serve (drinks), to put on (lipstick, etc.); to apply; to colour; to dye, to light (a fire); to burn, to shut; to close; to lock; to fasten, to stop in the midst of; to leave undone"},
    {"question":"咲く","answer":["さく"],"meaning":"to bloom"},
    {"meaning":"to be discovered","question":"見つかる","answer":["みつかる"]},
    {"meaning":"to discover","question":"見つける","answer":["みつける"]},
    {"meaning":"to stop","question":"止む","answer":["やむ"]},
    {"meaning":"use","question":"用","answer":["よう"]},
    {"meaning":"preparation","question":"用意","answer":["ようい"]},
    {"meaning":"things to do","question":"用事","answer":["ようじ"]},
    {"meaning":"Japanese hotel","question":"旅館","answer":["りょかん"]},
    {"meaning":"to separate","question":"別れる","answer":["わかれる"]},
    {"meaning":"to meet","question":"会う","answer":["あう"]},
    {"question":"吹く","answer":["ふく"],"meaning":"to blow (e.g. wind); to play a wind instrument, to emit; to spout, to whistle, to laugh; to burst into laughter, to smelt; to mint, to brag; to talk big"},
    {"question":"吸う","answer":["すう"],"meaning":"to smoke; to breathe in; to inhale, to suck; to sip; to slurp, to absorb; to soak up, to kiss"},
    {"meaning":"bright","question":"明い","answer":["あかるい"]},
    {"question":"切符","answer":["きっぷ"],"meaning":"ticket"},
    {"meaning":"to open","question":"開ける","answer":["あける"]},
    {"meaning":"morning","question":"朝","answer":["あさ"]},
    {"meaning":"foot, leg","question":"足","answer":["あし"]},
    {"meaning":"new","question":"新しい","answer":["あたらしい"]},
    {"question":"橋","answer":["はし"],"meaning":"bridge"},
    {"meaning":"(humble) older sister","question":"姉","answer":["あね"]},
    {"question":"歯","answer":["は"],"meaning":"tooth, (one's) age"},
    {"question":"首","answer":["くび","こうべ"],"meaning":"neck, head, dismissal; discharge; firing (from a job)"},
    {"meaning":"medical doctor","question":"医者","answer":["いしゃ"]},
    {"question":"飛行場","answer":["ひこうじょう"],"meaning":"airfield; airport"},
    {"meaning":"meaning","question":"意味","answer":["いみ"]},
    {"question":"集まる","answer":["あつまる"],"meaning":"to gather; to collect; to assemble"},
    {"meaning":"entrance","question":"入口","answer":["いりぐち"]},
    {"meaning":"colour","question":"色","answer":["いろ"]},
    {"question":"降り出す","answer":["ふりだす"],"meaning":"to begin to rain; to begin to snow"},
    {"question":"間に合う","answer":["まにあう"],"meaning":"to be in time for, to serve (suit, meet) the purpose; to be good enough; to be enough"},
    {"question":"金持ち","answer":["かねもち"],"meaning":"rich person"},
    {"question":"部長","answer":["ぶちょう"],"meaning":"head (chief, director) of a section or department, head of a (school) club; head of a (school) team"},
    {"meaning":"jacket","question":"上着","answer":["うわぎ"]},
    {"question":"選ぶ","answer":["えらぶ"],"meaning":"to choose; to select"},
    {"meaning":"cinema","question":"映画館","answer":["えいがかん"]},
    {"question":"遊び","answer":["あそび"],"meaning":"playing, play (margin between on and off, gap before pressing button or lever has an effect)"},
    {"question":"遅れる","answer":["おくれる"],"meaning":"to be late; to be delayed; to fall behind schedule; to be overdue"},
    {"meaning":"many","question":"多い","answer":["おおい"]},
    {"meaning":"to get up","question":"起きる","answer":["おきる"]},
    {"meaning":"to teach, to tell","question":"教える","answer":["おしえる"]},
    {"question":"進む","answer":["すすむ"],"meaning":"to advance; to go forward, to precede; to go ahead (of), to make progress; to improve, to deepen; to heighten, to be fast (of a clock); to be ahead, to do of one's own free will, to grow wild; to run to waste"},
    {"meaning":"younger brother","question":"弟","answer":["おとうと","おと"]},
    {"meaning":"same","question":"同じ","answer":["おなじ"]},
    {"question":"連絡","answer":["れんらく"],"meaning":"to contact; to get in touch, contacting; getting in touch; communication; call; message, connection; coordination; junction, intercalary; intercalaris; internuncial"},
    {"question":"込む","answer":["こむ"],"meaning":"to be crowded; to be packed, to be complex, to go into; to put into; to remain (seated); to be plunged into (silence); to do thoroughly, to do intently, to continue in the same state"},
    {"meaning":"Heavy","question":"重い","answer":["おもい"]},
    {"meaning":"to finish","question":"終わる","answer":["おわる"]},
    {"meaning":"Music","question":"音楽","answer":["おんがく"]},
    {"meaning":"Company","question":"会社","answer":["かいしゃ"]},
    {"meaning":"Shopping","question":"買い物","answer":["かいもの"]},
    {"question":"踊る","answer":["おどる"],"meaning":"to dance (orig. a hopping dance)"},
    {"question":"踊り","answer":["おどり"],"meaning":"dance"},
    {"meaning":"to lend","question":"貸す","answer":["かす"]},
    {"question":"趣味","answer":["しゅみ"],"meaning":"hobby; pastime, tastes; preference; liking"},
    {"meaning":"Family","question":"家族","answer":["かぞく"]},
    {"meaning":"person, way of doing","question":"方","answer":["かた","ほう"]},
    {"meaning":"paper","question":"紙","answer":["かみ"]},
    {"question":"起こす","answer":["おこす"],"meaning":"to raise; to raise up; to set up; to pick up, to wake; to wake up; to waken; to awaken, to cause; to bring about; to lead to; to trigger; to give rise to; to create; to generate (e.g. heat, electricity); to produce, to start; to begin; to launch; to establish; to found; to set up; to open, to plough; to plow; to till, to fall ill with, to transcribe; to write down (what is spoken), to turn over (a card)"},
    {"meaning":"Body","question":"体","answer":["からだ","てい"]},
    {"meaning":"to borrow","question":"借りる","answer":["かりる"]},
    {"meaning":"Chinese character","question":"漢字","answer":["かんじ"]},
    {"meaning":"postage stamp","question":"切手","answer":["きって"]},
    {"meaning":"Beef","question":"牛肉","answer":["ぎゅうにく"]},
    {"meaning":"Classroom","question":"教室","answer":["きょうしつ"]},
    {"meaning":"(humble) siblings","question":"兄弟","answer":["きょうだい"]},
    {"meaning":"last year","question":"去年","answer":["きょねん"]},
    {"meaning":"to cut","question":"切る","answer":["きる"]},
    {"meaning":"to put on from the shoulders down","question":"着る","answer":["きる"]},
    {"meaning":"Bank","question":"銀行","answer":["ぎんこう"]},
    {"question":"赤ん坊","answer":["あかんぼう"],"meaning":"baby; infant"},
    {"question":"負ける","answer":["まける"],"meaning":"to lose; to be defeated, to succumb; to give in; to surrender; to yield, to be inferior to, to break out in a rash due to (e.g. lacquer, shaving, etc.), to reduce the price; to give a discount; to throw in (something extra) for free"},
    {"meaning":"Black","question":"黒","answer":["くろ"]},
    {"meaning":"black","question":"黒い","answer":["くろい"]},
    {"meaning":"this morning","question":"今朝","answer":["けさ"]},
    {"meaning":"Monday","question":"月曜日","answer":["げつようび"]},
    {"question":"課長","answer":["かちょう"],"meaning":"section manager; section chief"},
    {"question":"説明","answer":["せつめい"],"meaning":"explanation; exposition"},
    {"meaning":"this week","question":"今週","answer":["こんしゅう"]},
    {"meaning":"Fish","question":"魚","answer":["さかな","うお"]},
    {"meaning":"composition, writing","question":"作文","answer":["さくぶん"]},
    {"question":"試合","answer":["しあい"],"meaning":"match; game; bout; contest"},
    {"meaning":"Question","question":"質問","answer":["しつもん"]},
    {"meaning":"Bicycle","question":"自転車","answer":["じてんしゃ"]},
    {"meaning":"Automobile","question":"自動車","answer":["じどうしゃ"]},
    {"meaning":"to die","question":"死ぬ","answer":["しぬ"]},
    {"meaning":"photograph","question":"写真","answer":["しゃしん"]},
    {"meaning":"Skillful","question":"上手","answer":["じょうず","うわて"]},
    {"meaning":"dining hall","question":"食堂","answer":["しょくどう"]},
    {"meaning":"to know","question":"知る","answer":["しる"]},
    {"meaning":"newspaper","question":"新聞","answer":["しんぶん"]},
    {"question":"触る","answer":["さわる"],"meaning":"to touch; to feel"},
    {"meaning":"a few","question":"少ない","answer":["すくない"]},
    {"question":"裏","answer":["うら"],"meaning":"bottom (or another side that is hidden from view); undersurface; opposite side; reverse side, rear; back; behind (the house), lining; inside, out of sight; behind the scenes; in the shadows, proof, opposite (of a prediction, common sense, etc.), inverse (of a hypothesis, etc.), bottom (of an inning); last half (of an inning)"},
    {"meaning":"to live in","question":"住む","answer":["すむ"]},
    {"meaning":"last week","question":"先週","answer":["せんしゅう"]},
    {"meaning":"sky (そら), emptiness (から)","question":"空","answer":["そら","から"]},
    {"meaning":"embassy","question":"大使館","answer":["たいしかん"]},
    {"meaning":"important","question":"大切","answer":["たいせつ"]},
    {"meaning":"to stand","question":"立つ","answer":["たつ"]},
    {"meaning":"building","question":"建物","answer":["たてもの"]},
    {"meaning":"enjoyable","question":"楽しい","answer":["たのしい"]},
    {"question":"血","answer":["ち"],"meaning":"blood; consanguinity"},
    {"meaning":"near","question":"近い","answer":["ちかい"]},
    {"meaning":"near","question":"近く","answer":["ちかく"]},
    {"meaning":"map","question":"地図","answer":["ちず"]},
    {"meaning":"brown","question":"茶色","answer":["ちゃいろ"]},
    {"meaning":"to use","question":"使う","answer":["つかう"]},
    {"meaning":"to arrive at","question":"着く","answer":["つく"]},
    {"meaning":"to make","question":"作る","answer":["つくる"]},
    {"meaning":"powerful","question":"強い","answer":["つよい"]},
    {"question":"虫","answer":["むし"],"meaning":"insect; bug; cricket; moth; worm"},
    {"meaning":"letter","question":"手紙","answer":["てがみ"]},
    {"meaning":"exit","question":"出口","answer":["でぐち"]},
    {"meaning":"animal","question":"動物","answer":["どうぶつ"]},
    {"meaning":"watch, clock","question":"時計","answer":["とけい"]},
    {"meaning":"library","question":"図書館","answer":["としょかん"]},
    {"question":"葉","answer":["は"],"meaning":"leaf, counter for leaves, pieces of paper, etc., counter for boats"},
    {"question":"落ちる","answer":["おちる"],"meaning":"to fall down; to drop; to fall (e.g. rain); to sink (e.g. sun or moon); to fall onto (e.g. light or one's gaze); to be used in a certain place (e.g. money), to be omitted; to be missing, to decrease; to sink, to fail (e.g. exam or class); to lose (contest, election, etc.), to crash; to degenerate; to degrade; to fall behind, to become indecent (of a conversation), to be ruined; to go under, to fade; to come out (e.g. a stain); to come off (e.g. makeup); to be removed (e.g. illness, possessing spirit, name on a list), to fall (into someone's hands); to become someone's possession, to fall (into a trap); to fall (for a trick), to give in; to give up; to confess; to flee, to fall; to be defeated; to surrender, to come to (in the end); to end in, to fall (in love, asleep, etc.), to swoon (judo), to consent; to understand, to crash; to freeze, to die, to move to the depths"},
    {"meaning":"bird","question":"鳥","answer":["とり"]},
    {"meaning":"chicken meat","question":"とり肉","answer":["とりにく"]},
    {"question":"落す","answer":["おとす"],"meaning":"to drop; to lose; to let fall; to shed (light); to cast (one's gaze); to pour in (liquid); to leave behind, to clean off (dirt, makeup, paint, etc.); to remove (e.g. stains or facial hair); to lose; to spend money at a certain place; to omit; to leave out; to secretly let escape, to lose (a match); to reject (an applicant); to fail (a course); to defeat (in an election), to lower (e.g. shoulders or voice); to lessen (e.g. production or body weight); to worsen (quality); to reduce (e.g. rank or popularity); to speak badly of; to make light of; to fall into straitened circumstances, to fall into (e.g. a dilemma or sin); to make one's own; to have one's bid accepted; to force surrender; to take (e.g. an enemy camp or castle); to forcefully convince; to press for a confession; to deal with, to download; to copy from a computer to another medium, to make someone swoon (judo), to finish a story (e.g. with the punch line), to finish (a period, e.g. of fasting)"},
    {"meaning":"summer holiday","question":"夏休み","answer":["なつやすみ"]},
    {"meaning":"to learn","question":"習う","answer":["ならう"]},
    {"question":"草","answer":["くさ"],"meaning":"grass; weed; herb; thatch, ninja, not genuine; substandard, laughter; LOL, draft; rough copy, cursive script; \"grass\" kanji"},
    {"question":"船","answer":["ふね"],"meaning":"ship; boat; watercraft; vessel; steamship, tank; tub; vat; trough, counter for boat-shaped containers (e.g. of sashimi)"},
    {"question":"興味","answer":["きょうみ"],"meaning":"interest (in something); curiosity (about something); zest (for)"},
    {"question":"腕","answer":["うで"],"meaning":"arm, skill; efforts; ability, arm (esp. upper arm), counter used to measure the thickness of round objects"},
    {"meaning":"to begin","question":"始まる","answer":["はじまる"]},
    {"meaning":"beginning","question":"始め","answer":["はじめ"]},
    {"question":"背中","answer":["せなか"],"meaning":"back (of body)"},
    {"meaning":"flower","question":"花","answer":["はな"]},
    {"meaning":"early","question":"早い","answer":["はやい"]},
    {"question":"美しい","answer":["うつくしい"],"meaning":"beautiful; lovely"},
    {"meaning":"hospital","question":"病院","answer":["びょういん"]},
    {"meaning":"illness","question":"病気","answer":["びょうき"]},
    {"meaning":"noon, daytime","question":"昼","answer":["ひる"]},
    {"meaning":"spacious, wide","question":"広い","answer":["ひろい"]},
    {"meaning":"clothes","question":"服","answer":["ふく"]},
    {"question":"線","answer":["せん"],"meaning":"line; stripe; stria, line (e.g. telephone line); wire, ray (e.g. X-ray); beam, line (e.g. of a railroad); track; route; lane, outline; contours; form, level, division, line (of action); position; approach; policy; principle, impression one leaves; air one gives off"},
    {"meaning":"old (not used for people)","question":"古い","answer":["ふるい"]},
    {"meaning":"unskillful","question":"下手","answer":["へた"]},
    {"meaning":"to study","question":"勉強","answer":["べんきょう"]},
    {"meaning":"every morning","question":"毎朝","answer":["まいあさ"]},
    {"meaning":"every week","question":"毎週","answer":["まいしゅう"]},
    {"meaning":"town, city","question":"町","answer":["まち"]},
    {"meaning":"to wait","question":"待つ","answer":["まつ"]},
    {"question":"続ける","answer":["つづける"],"meaning":"to continue; to keep up; to keep on"},
    {"question":"続く","answer":["つづく"],"meaning":"to continue; to last; to go on, to continue (without a break); to be unbroken, to occur again and again, to lead to; to connect to; to adjoin, to come after; to follow; to succeed; to rank next to, to hold out; to keep; to last"},
    {"question":"紹介","answer":["しょうかい"],"meaning":"introduction; presentation; referral; listing"},
    {"meaning":"again","question":"もう一度","answer":["もういちど"]},
    {"question":"約束","answer":["やくそく"],"meaning":"promise; agreement; arrangement; one's word; contract; pact; appointment; engagement; date, convention; rule, destiny; fate"},
    {"meaning":"to hold","question":"持つ","answer":["もつ"]},
    {"meaning":"thing","question":"物","answer":["もの"]},
    {"meaning":"problem","question":"問題","answer":["もんだい"]},
    {"meaning":"greengrocer","question":"八百屋","answer":["やおや"]},
    {"question":"簡単","answer":["かんたん"],"meaning":"simple; easy; uncomplicated, brief; quick; light"},
    {"meaning":"evening","question":"夕方","answer":["ゆうがた"]},
    {"meaning":"dinner","question":"夕飯","answer":["ゆうはん"]},
    {"meaning":"famous","question":"有名","answer":["ゆうめい"]},
    {"meaning":"western-style clothes","question":"洋服","answer":["ようふく"]},
    {"meaning":"evening, night","question":"夜","answer":["よる","よ"]},
    {"meaning":"next week","question":"来週","answer":["らいしゅう"]},
    {"meaning":"cuisine","question":"料理","answer":["りょうり"]},
    {"meaning":"travel","question":"旅行","answer":["りょこう"]},
    {"meaning":"bad","question":"悪い","answer":["わるい","にくい"]},
    {"question":"お礼","answer":["おれい"],"meaning":"thanks; gratitude, manners; etiquette, bow, reward; gift, ceremony; ritual"},
    {"question":"お祝い","answer":["おいわい"],"meaning":"congratulation; congratulations; celebration; festival; congratulatory gift"},
    {"question":"お祭り","answer":["おまつり"],"meaning":"festival; feast; carnival"},
    {"question":"ご主人","answer":["ごしゅじん"],"meaning":"your husband; her husband"},
    {"question":"答え","answer":["こたえ"],"meaning":"answer; reply; response; solution"},
    {"question":"笑う","answer":["わらう"],"meaning":"to laugh, to smile, to sneer; to ridicule, to be dumbfounded; to be flabbergasted"},
    {"question":"砂","answer":["すな"],"meaning":"sand; grit, gold dust; silver dust"},
    {"question":"上がる","answer":["あがる"],"meaning":"to rise; to go up; to come up; to ascend; to be raised, to enter (esp. from outdoors); to come in; to go in, to enter (a school); to advance to the next grade, to get out (of water); to come ashore, to increase, to improve; to make progress, to be promoted; to advance, to be made (of profit, etc.), to occur (esp. of a favourable result), to be adequate (to cover expenses, etc.), to be finished; to be done; to be over, (of rain) to stop; to lift, to stop (working properly); to cut out; to give out; to die, to win (in a card game, etc.), to be spoken loudly, to get stage fright, to be offered (to the gods, etc.), to go; to visit, to eat; to drink, to be listed (as a candidate), to serve (in one's master's home), to go north, indicates completion"},
    {"question":"石","answer":["いし"],"meaning":"stone, gem; jewel, measure of volume (approx. 180.39 liters, 6.37 cub. ft.), measure of a Japanese-style boat's loading capacity (approx. 278.26 liters)"},
    {"question":"眠る","answer":["ねむる"],"meaning":"to sleep (not necessarily lying down), to die, to lie idle (e.g. of resources); to be dormant; to be unused, to close one's eyes"},
    {"question":"眠い","answer":["ねむい"],"meaning":"sleepy; drowsy; somnolent"},
    {"question":"久しぶり","answer":["ひさしぶり"],"meaning":"a long time (since the last time); it's been a while (since I last saw, mailed, etc., you)"},
    {"question":"乗り物","answer":["のりもの"],"meaning":"vehicle; conveyance; transport, ride (playground, fair, carnival); playground facility"},
    {"question":"真ん中","answer":["まんなか"],"meaning":"middle; centre; center; mid-way"},
    {"question":"事故","answer":["じこ"],"meaning":"accident; incident; trouble, circumstances; reasons"},
    {"question":"二階建て","answer":["にかいだて"],"meaning":"two-storied building"},
    {"question":"皆","answer":["みな","みんな"],"meaning":"all; everyone; everybody, everything"},
    {"question":"交通","answer":["こうつう"],"meaning":"traffic; transportation; communication; exchange (of ideas, etc.); intercourse"},
    {"question":"番組","answer":["ばんぐみ"],"meaning":"program (e.g. TV); programme"},
    {"question":"生活","answer":["せいかつ"],"meaning":"living; life (one's daily existence); livelihood"},
    {"question":"伝える","answer":["つたえる"],"meaning":"to convey; to report; to transmit; to communicate; to tell; to impart; to propagate; to teach; to bequeath"},
    {"question":"似る","answer":["にる"],"meaning":"to resemble; to look like; to take after, to be similar (in status, condition, etc.); to be close; to be alike; to be like"},
    {"question":"片付ける","answer":["かたづける"],"meaning":"to tidy up; to put in order; to straighten up; to put away, to settle (problem); to clear (dispute), to finish; to bring something to an end, to marry off (e.g. a daughter), to do away with someone; to bump someone off"},
    {"question":"点","answer":["てん"],"meaning":"dot; point; mark, gidayuu musicians (in kabuki), spot; mark, point; dot, mark (e.g. in exam); score; points, comma, aspect; matter; respect, counter for goods, items, articles of clothing, works of art, etc., dot; point; mark, tip; gratuity, a little; paltry; piddling; mere"},
    {"question":"漫画","answer":["まんが"],"meaning":"cartoon; comic; comic strip"},
    {"question":"優しい","answer":["やさしい"],"meaning":"tender; kind; gentle; graceful; affectionate; amiable"},
    {"question":"先輩","answer":["せんぱい"],"meaning":"senior (at work or school); superior; elder; older graduate; progenitor; old-timer"},
    {"question":"光","answer":["ひかり"],"meaning":"light, illumination; ray; beam; gleam; glow, happiness; hope, influence; power, vision; eyesight"},
    {"question":"光る","answer":["ひかる"],"meaning":"to shine; to glitter; to be bright"},
    {"question":"具合","answer":["ぐあい"],"meaning":"condition; state; manner; health"},
    {"question":"内","answer":["うち"],"meaning":"inside; within, while, among; amongst; between, we (referring to one's in-group, e.g. company, etc.); our, my spouse, imperial palace grounds, emperor, I (primarily used by women and children); me, inside; within"},
    {"question":"冷たい","answer":["つめたい"],"meaning":"cold (to the touch); chilly; icy; freezing, coldhearted; unfeeling"},
    {"question":"湯","answer":["ゆ"],"meaning":"hot water, hot bath; hot spring, molten iron, soup"},
    {"question":"動物園","answer":["どうぶつえん"],"meaning":"zoo; zoological gardens"},
    {"question":"勝つ","answer":["かつ"],"meaning":"to win; to gain victory"},
    {"question":"包む","answer":["つつむ","くるむ"],"meaning":"to wrap up; to tuck in; to pack; to do up; to cover with; to dress in, to conceal; to hide; to be engulfed in; to be enveloped by, to wrap up; to tuck in; to pack; to do up; to cover with; to dress in"},
    {"question":"十分","answer":["じゅうぶん","じゅっぷん","じっぷん"],"meaning":"10 minutes, plenty; enough; sufficient; satisfactory; adequate, division into ten, perfectly; thoroughly; fully; in full"},
    {"question":"卒業","answer":["そつぎょう"],"meaning":"graduation; completion (e.g. of a course), outgrowing something; moving on"},
    {"question":"危険","answer":["きけん"],"meaning":"danger; peril; hazard, risk"},
    {"question":"受ける","answer":["うける"],"meaning":"to receive; to get, to catch (e.g. a ball), to be struck by (wind, waves, sunlight, etc.), to sustain (damage); to incur (a loss); to suffer (an injury); to feel (influence), to undergo (e.g. surgery); to take (a test); to accept (a challenge), to be given (e.g. life, talent), to follow; to succeed; to be descended from, to face (south, etc.), to be modified by, to obtain (a pawned item, etc.) by paying a fee, to be well-received; to become popular; to go down well, to be funny; to be humorous"},
    {"question":"湖","answer":["みずうみ"],"meaning":"lake, lake (in place names)"},
    {"question":"召し上がる","answer":["めしあがる"],"meaning":"to eat; to drink"},
    {"question":"合う","answer":["あう"],"meaning":"to come together; to merge; to unite; to meet, to fit; to match; to suit; to agree with; to be correct, to be profitable; to be equitable, to do ... to each other; to do ... together"},
    {"question":"向かう","answer":["むかう"],"meaning":"to face, to go towards; to head towards"},
    {"question":"君","answer":["きみ"],"meaning":"you; buddy; pal, monarch; ruler; sovereign; (one's) master, Mr (junior); master; boy, suffix appended to somebody else's family members, you"},
    {"question":"周り","answer":["まわり"],"meaning":"circumference; girth, surroundings; neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity"},
    {"question":"困る","answer":["こまる"],"meaning":"to be troubled; to be worried; to be bothered; to be embarrassed; to be stumped"},
    {"question":"固い","answer":["かたい"],"meaning":"hard; solid; tough, stiff; tight; wooden; unpolished (e.g. writing), strong; firm (not viscous or easily moved), safe; steady; honest; steadfast, obstinate; stubborn, bookish; formal; stuffy"},
    {"question":"地震","answer":["じしん"],"meaning":"earthquake"},
    {"question":"坂","answer":["さか"],"meaning":"slope; hill"},
    {"question":"深い","answer":["ふかい"],"meaning":"deep, profound, dense; thick, close (relationship), intense; strong, late"},
    {"question":"場所","answer":["ばしょ"],"meaning":"place; location; spot; position, room; space, basho; wrestling tournament"},
    {"question":"消しゴム","answer":["けしゴム"],"meaning":"eraser; India rubber"},
    {"question":"声","answer":["こえ"],"meaning":"voice"},
    {"question":"変","answer":["へん"],"meaning":"strange; odd; peculiar; weird; curious; queer; eccentric; funny; suspicious; fishy, unexpected, change, incident; disturbance; disaster; accident, flat"},
    {"question":"変える","answer":["かえる"],"meaning":"to change; to alter; to transform; to convert; to turn; to vary, to reform; to revise; to amend"},
    {"question":"変わる","answer":["かわる"],"meaning":"to change; to be transformed; to be altered; to vary, to move to, to be different; to be uncommon; to be unusual"},
    {"question":"夢","answer":["ゆめ"],"meaning":"dream"},
    {"question":"太る","answer":["ふとる"],"meaning":"to grow fat (stout, plump); to become fat; to gain weight"},
    {"question":"泣く","answer":["なく"],"meaning":"to cry; to weep; to sob; to howl"},
    {"question":"娘","answer":["むすめ"],"meaning":"(my) daughter, girl (i.e. a young, unmarried woman)"},
    {"question":"安全","answer":["あんぜん"],"meaning":"safety, security"},
    {"question":"客","answer":["きゃく"],"meaning":"guest; visitor, customer; client; shopper; spectator; audience; tourist; sightseer; passenger, visitor from afar; guest, visitor from afar, joy-bringing spirit from the divine realms"},
    {"question":"寺","answer":["てら"],"meaning":"temple (Buddhist), counter for temples"},
    {"question":"将来","answer":["しょうらい"],"meaning":"future (usually near); prospects"},
    {"question":"小説","answer":["しょうせつ"],"meaning":"novel; (short) story"},
    {"question":"届ける","answer":["とどける"],"meaning":"to deliver; to forward; to send, to report; to notify; to file notice (to the authorities); to give notice; to register"},
    {"question":"島","answer":["しま"],"meaning":"island, territory (of a prostitute, organized crime gang, etc.); turf, Island, insula; island; islet"},
    {"question":"泊まる","answer":["とまる"],"meaning":"to stay at (e.g. hotel), to be docked; to be berthed; to be moored"},
    {"question":"決める","answer":["きめる"],"meaning":"to decide; to choose; to determine; to make up one's mind; to resolve; to set one's heart on; to settle; to arrange; to set; to appoint; to fix, to clinch (a victory); to decide (the outcome of a match), to persist in doing; to go through with, to always do; to have made a habit of, to take for granted; to assume, to dress up; to dress to kill; to dress to the nines, to carry out successfully (a move in sports, a pose in dance, etc.); to succeed in doing, to immobilize with a double-arm lock (in sumo, judo, etc.), to eat or drink something; to take illegal drugs"},
    {"question":"布団","answer":["ふとん"],"meaning":"futon (quilted Japanese-style mattress laid out on the floor), round cushion used for Zen meditation (traditionally made of woven bulrush leaves)"},
    {"question":"席","answer":["せき"],"meaning":"seat, location (of a gathering, etc.); place, position; post, woven mat (esp. one made of straw), seat"},
    {"question":"引き出し","answer":["ひきだし"],"meaning":"drawer, withdrawal; drawing out, variety of knowledge and experience useful for handling things impromptu"},
    {"question":"決まる","answer":["きまる"],"meaning":"to be decided; to be settled, to look good in (clothes)"},
    {"question":"気分","answer":["きぶん"],"meaning":"feeling; mood"},
    {"question":"役に立つ","answer":["やくにたつ"],"meaning":"to be helpful; to be useful"},
    {"question":"彼","answer":["かれ"],"meaning":"that (indicating something distant from both speaker and listener (in space, time or psychologically), or something understood without naming it directly), that person (used to refer to one's equals or inferiors), over there, down there (i.e. one's genitals), period; menses, hey (expression of surprise, suspicion, etc.); huh?; eh?, that (something mentioned before which is distant psychologically or in terms of time), he; him, his, boyfriend"},
    {"question":"彼女","answer":["かのじょ"],"meaning":"she; her, her, girlfriend; sweetheart"},
    {"question":"復習","answer":["ふくしゅう"],"meaning":"review; revision"},
    {"question":"忘れ物","answer":["わすれもの"],"meaning":"lost article; something forgotten"},
    {"question":"怒る","answer":["おこる","いかる"],"meaning":"to get angry; to get mad, to tell someone off; to scold, to be angular; to be square"},
    {"question":"怖い","answer":["こわい"],"meaning":"scary; frightening; eerie; dreadful, (I'm) afraid"},
    {"question":"恥ずかしい","answer":["はずかしい"],"meaning":"shy; ashamed; embarrassed, disgraceful; shameful"},
    {"question":"息子","answer":["むすこ"],"meaning":"son, penis"},
    {"question":"悲しい","answer":["かなしい"],"meaning":"sad; sorrowful"},
    {"question":"毛","answer":["け","もう"],"meaning":"hair, fur; wool, down; plumage; feathers, one-thousandth; 0.03 mm (one-thousandth of a sun); 0.01 percent (one-thousandth of a wari); 3.75 milligrams (one-thousandth of a monme), old monetary unit (0.0001 yen)"},
    {"question":"残る","answer":["のこる"],"meaning":"to remain; to be left"},
    {"question":"戻る","answer":["もどる"],"meaning":"to turn back (e.g. half-way), to return; to go back, to recover (e.g. something lost); to be returned, to rebound; to spring back, to go against; to act contrary to; to deviate from; to oppose"},
    {"question":"手伝う","answer":["てつだう"],"meaning":"to help; to assist; to aid, to contribute to; to be a factor in"},
    {"question":"手袋","answer":["てぶくろ"],"meaning":"glove; mitten; mitt"},
    {"question":"打つ","answer":["うつ","ぶつ"],"meaning":"to hit; to strike; to knock; to beat; to punch; to slap; to tap; to bang; to clap; to pound, to strike (noon, etc.); to sound (cymbals, etc.); to beat (a drum, etc.), to beat (rhythmically, e.g. pulse, waves, etc.), to move; to impress; to touch, to drive in; to hammer in; to put in; to inject, to type; to send; to transmit, to insert; to write in; to mark, to make (noodles, etc.); to prepare, to till (soil), to sprinkle; to throw; to cast, to do; to carry out; to play; to perform; to engage in (gambling, etc.), to pay (a deposit, etc.), to visit (on a pilgrimage), to line (a coat), to bind (a criminal), to hit (a person); to strike; to beat"},
    {"question":"払う","answer":["はらう"],"meaning":"to pay (e.g. money, bill), to brush off; to wipe away; to clear away; to dust off; to cut off (e.g. branches), to drive away (e.g. one's competitors), to sell off (something unneeded); to dispose of, to pay (e.g. attention); to show (e.g. respect, concern), to make (e.g. effort, sacrifice); to expend; to exert, to move out (of one's own place); to vacate, to sweep (e.g. one's legs); to knock aside, to make a sweeping stroke (in Japanese calligraphy), to reset (an abacus)"},
    {"question":"押し入れ","answer":["おしいれ"],"meaning":"closet"},
    {"question":"拾う","answer":["ひろう"],"meaning":"to pick up; to find; to gather"},
    {"question":"指","answer":["ゆび"],"meaning":"finger; toe; digit, between (e.g. two people); face to face, hindrance; impediment, arrhythmic section of recitative in noh music, prefix used for stress or emphasis, counter for traditional dance songs"},
    {"question":"指輪","answer":["ゆびわ"],"meaning":"(finger) ring"},
    {"question":"探す","answer":["さがす"],"meaning":"to search (for something desired, needed); to look for, to search (for something lost); to seek (a suspect in a crime)"},
    {"question":"故障","answer":["こしょう"],"meaning":"breakdown; failure; fault; accident; out of order, damage; hurt, objection; protest"},
    {"question":"歴史","answer":["れきし"],"meaning":"history"},
    {"question":"数学","answer":["すうがく"],"meaning":"mathematics; arithmetic"},
    {"question":"文化","answer":["ぶんか"],"meaning":"culture; civilization; civilisation, Bunka era (1804.2.11-1818.4.22)"},
    {"question":"楽しむ","answer":["たのしむ"],"meaning":"to enjoy (oneself)"},
    {"question":"日記","answer":["にっき"],"meaning":"diary; journal"},
    {"question":"森","answer":["もり"],"meaning":"forest, shrine grove"},
    {"question":"星","answer":["ほし"],"meaning":"star; any light-emitting (or reflecting) heavenly body (except for the sun and the moon), offender; perpetrator, star point (in go); hoshi; intersection marked with a dot, circular symbol (said to be shaped like a shining star), bullseye, one's star (out of the nine stars); the star that determines one's fate, small dot; spot, point; score, Chinese \"star\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions), Singapore"},
    {"question":"普通","answer":["ふつう"],"meaning":"general; ordinary; usual, normally; generally; usually, local train; train that stops at every station"},
    {"question":"机","answer":["つくえ"],"meaning":"desk"},
    {"question":"林","answer":["はやし"],"meaning":"woods; forest; copse; thicket, bunch; line (of something); collection"},
    {"question":"枝","answer":["えだ"],"meaning":"branch; bow; bough; twig; limb, counter for long, thin things (i.e. swords)"}
  ]
}
